Douglas Rosenberg

1159 Lyman Ave., Oak Park, IL 60304

Phone: 773-627-4279 | Email: <u>Doug.rosenberg@gmail.com</u>

Linked In: www.linkedin.com/in/douglas-rosenberg

Portfolio: doug-rosenberg-portfolio.herokuapp.com | Github: github.com/shalant

Summary

Full Stack Junior Web Developer with a background in Music and BS in Chemistry.

I've spent 20 years performing and teaching music. A few highlights are performing at private events, managing a band, touring, and giving masterclasses at Princeton and Michigan, in addition to 100's of private saxophone students.

Technical skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Applications: React, Node, Mysql, Express, MongoDB, Jquery, Npm, Bootstrap, Axios, Jest, Excel, Git, Heroku

Projects

Dynamic Wine | github.com/shalant/dynamicwine | dynamicwine.herokuapp.com

-Final group project, utilizing MERN stack, google maps, helps a restaurant sell its wine list

Informed Trades | github.com/shalant/Informed Trades | shalant.github.io/Informed Trades

-First group project that offers news articles for a given stocker ticker symbol.

Employee Directory | shalant.github.io/employee directory react | shalant.github.io/employee directory react/

-A beginner React app that can sort through a DB of employees

Scheduler App | github.com/shalant/SchedulerApp | shalant.github.io/SchedulerApp

-This app created a daily calendar application and did a few interesting things

Experience

- -Saxophonist for private events: 2000-present, hired by companies and musicians to play professional music for weddings and corporate events
- -Band leader, composer, soloist: 2000-present, recorded an album of original jazzy music entitled "Better Than TV," presented masterclasses at Princeton, Michigan, Cornell, and 50 other colleges, toured extensively with the band Eastern Blok, performances at Millenium Park, the Metro, 30 shows in NYC (Knitting Factory, Joe's Pub, etc.)
- -Private teacher in saxophone lessons, clarinet/flute, jazz improvisation, jazz ensembles: 2000-present

Education

Bootcamp Certificate (pending): Northwestern University Coding Bootcamp, Evanston, IL

B.S. in Chemistry, Tufts University, Boston, MA, 1997-2001

B.M. in Jazz Saxophone, New England Conservatory of Music, Boston, MA, 1997-2001